<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code, Compute, Create on Ted Moore | Composer, Improviser, Intermedia Artist</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Code, Compute, Create on Ted Moore | Composer, Improviser, Intermedia Artist</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Ted Moore. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learned Navigation of StyleGAN3 Latent Space from Audio Descriptors</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/learned-navigation-stylegan3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/learned-navigation-stylegan3/</guid><description>In September 2025, I presented a paper at the 6th Artificial Intelligence and Music Creativity Conference, which was held in Brussels Belgium. My paper described a process creating an audio reactive video (for the fourth movement of arco) using some machine learning in an attempt to intimately link the audio and video morphologies.
You can read the full paper here: Learned Navigation of StyleGAN3 Latent Space from Audio Descriptors
Screenshot of SuperCollider program developed for creating the audio reactive video.</description></item><item><title>Rendering Scores with Jinja Templates</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/score-rendering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/score-rendering/</guid><description>I used to create scores by exporting the Sibelius files as PDFs and then importing them into Adobe InDesign to add the cover, front matter, tech rider, etc. (I know it&amp;rsquo;s possible to do all this in Sibelius&amp;hellip; I like to have a bit more control on the layout, formatting, etc.) The issue I had with this was that if I changed any little thing in the score I had to go through the whole process of importing and exporting through InDesign.</description></item><item><title>_alloy_ the album</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/alloy-album/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/alloy-album/</guid><description>After having performed alloy many times with Kyle, we decided to record a whole album of just feedback cymbal + saxophone multiphonics.
Track 1 from alloy:
Your browser does not support the audio element. see the code referenced below.
Multiphonic Similarity Lookup The main technological idea behind the album was to use a system that would analyze the &amp;ldquo;pitch class content&amp;rdquo; of the feedback cymbal in real-time, find the saxophone multiphonic with the most similar pitch class content, and display it to the saxophonist to perform, (perhaps) blending harmonically with the cymbal (I say perhaps because the microtonality of the cymbal and multiphonics makes for some juicy proximities).</description></item><item><title>_Musical Agents, Agency, &amp; AI: Towards a Phenomenological Understanding_</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/agency/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/agency/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the paper I presented at ICMC 2024 titled, Musical Agents, Agency, &amp;amp; AI: Towards a Phenomenological Understanding.
Read Full Paper
abstract:
Creating AI musical agents is an interest to many electronic music artists and researchers. This paper suggests a phenomenological understanding of &amp;ldquo;musical agency&amp;rdquo; determined by four criteria: in order to perceive a technological system as a collaborative agent it must (1) be perceived as separate from the user, (2) be surprising to the user, (3) be intended as a collaborative agent, and (4) mirror the user’s own musical intentions.</description></item><item><title>Adapting _saccades_ for the Allosphere</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/allosphere/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/allosphere/</guid><description>published May 15, 2025
In spring of 2024 I was asked to present saccades in the Allosphere: a three-story, 360 degree video sphere with 54 channel surround sound at UC Santa Barbara. The audience watches from a bridge that goes directly through the middle of the sphere. My saxophone-playing collaborator Kyle Hutchins was doing a west coast tour and though it would be cool to bring saccades to this very tech-forward space.</description></item><item><title>Creating *quartet*</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/creating-quartet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/creating-quartet/</guid><description>published May 15, 2025
I created quartet in collaboration with the [Switch Ensemble~] for the 2021 SEAMUS Conference which was held online because of the pandemic. Because I knew that the work&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;premiere&amp;rdquo; would be held as a prerecorded video concert on YouTube, I decided to approach the work not as a live, electro-acoustic composition, but as a fixed-media, video-art piece that made use of the of the necessary technological mediation at play.</description></item><item><title>The Harmonic Series Strikes Again</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/harmonic-series-strikes-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/blog/harmonic-series-strikes-again/</guid><description>published May 17, 2025
My composition hollow, includes large PVC tubes that are used in a complex audio feedback system. The three tubes (all four inches in diameter) are cut to lengths of 10 feet, 8.4 feet, and 7.5 feet in order to achieve resonances at 55.8 Hz (~A1), 66.3 Hz (~C2), and 74.4 Hz (~D2) respectively.
A recording of a performance of hollow was used as the tape part in the fifth movement of arco.</description></item></channel></rss>