<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>installation on Ted Moore | Composer, Improviser, Intermedia Artist</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/categories/installation/</link><description>Recent content in installation on Ted Moore | Composer, Improviser, Intermedia Artist</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Ted Moore. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><atom:link href="https://tedmoore.github.io/categories/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aluminum Forest</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/works/aluminum-forest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/works/aluminum-forest/</guid><description>created in collaboration with Katherine Balch.
Scores of hand-crafted aluminum chimes are placed all throughout the garden. Each is independently agitated by a small DC motor creating varying gestures, trajectories, and timbres. Motion sensors (connected to the motors through a small Arduino controller) trigger added agitation, acknowledging audiences presence and allowing them to participate in shaping the sonic environment. The Arduinos are also be controlled via WiFi enabling the entire system of chimes to be a performative space creating motions and gestures of sound that encompass the space and can adapt to different configuration of chimes and installation sites.</description></item><item><title>attackSUSTAINrelease</title><link>https://tedmoore.github.io/works/attacksustainrelease/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tedmoore.github.io/works/attacksustainrelease/</guid><description>At the pace of one taking deep breaths, brown noise swells in and out of each suspended raw speaker cone in an unpredictable pattern. With it, the water in the cones agitate and reflect light into shimmering patterns on the walls and ceiling. The minimalist presentation draws a strong causal relationship between all of the elements in the room: sound, water, light, and the physical functionality of speakers.</description></item></channel></rss>